Lorenzo Fabbri

Summary

I am a PhD student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal). I work under the supervision of Prof. Martine Vrijheid. My main topic of interest is the use of modern Causal Inference methods to answer questions in the broad field of Environmental Neuroepidemiology. I am also profoundly interested in Open Science and Reproducible Research.

I received my Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology and my Master's degree in Quantitative and Computational Biology.

My personal webpage is here. You can also find me on Twitter, Bluesky, Mastodon, and GitHub.

Working Experience

PhD Student

Barcelona Institute for Global Health (Barcelona, ES)

2021 - Present

- NA

Student Research Assistant Fellowship

Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

2017 - 2017

- NA

Honors and Awards

Outstanding Abstract by a Student

International Society for Environmental Epidemiology

2022

Publications

- 1. Fabbri L, Garlantézec R, Audouze K, et al. Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic profiles: A panel study. Environment International. Published online February 26, 2023:107856. doi:10.1016/j.envint.2023.107856
- 2. Thiel C, Cordes H, Fabbri L, et al. A Comparative Analysis of Drug-Induced Hepatotoxicity in Clinically Relevant Situations. PLOS Computational Biology. 2017;13(2):e1005280. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005280

Conference Presentations

Education

PhD Programme in Biomedicine

Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona, ES)

2021 - Present

- NA

M.Sc. in Quantitative and Computational Biology

Università degli Studi di Trento (Trento, IT)

2017 - 2019

- NA

M.Sc. Student in Computational Science

Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

2016 - 2017

- NA

B.Sc. in Biotechnology University of Parma (Parma, IT)

2012 - 2016

- NA

Continuing Education

Service

Skills